http://www.emirates.com/us/english/sitetools/privacy_policy.aspx

Accessibility informationSkip to the main contentPrivacy PolicyWe take your privacy seriously and are committed to protecting your personal information. Our Privacy Notice explains how we collect, use, and share personal information in the course of our business activities. In order to help you find what you are looking for, we have divided the information into several sections. These sections provide general information about us and how this Privacy Notice applies.AboutAbout the Emirates GroupProviding your personal informationUpdatesThird-Party WebsitesPersonal information we collect and usePersonal information we collect and use when you make a booking or fly with usPersonal information we collect and use if you create an online account with us or register for one of our loyalty programsPersonal information we collect and use if you have questions about any of our products or servicesPersonal information we collect and use when you enter or register for a contest, competition, prize drawing, or promotional offerPersonal information we collect and use on our flights or in our loungesPersonal information we collect and use if you send cargo with usPersonal information we collect and use in the event of an emergencyPersonal information we collect and use when you use our PlatformsPersonal information we collect and use for legal, compliance, regulatory, and crime detection and prevention purposesPersonal information we collect from third partiesPersonal information we collect and use when you are making a paymentPersonal information we collect and use during corporate events and activitiesMore informationOverviewLegal basis for using your personal informationSharing your personal information with othersHow we use personal information to keep you updated on our products and servicesHow you can manage your marketing preferencesWhen and how we undertake analytics and profilingTransferring personal information globallyHow we protect and store your personal informationCookiesYour legal rights to manage your privacyCalifornia Shine the Light DisclosureHow to contact usLegal Basis TableThe Emirates Group includes a number of related businesses:Emirates, whose principal office is at Emirates Group Headquarters, PO Box 686, Dubai, United Arab Emirates. Emirates is a Dubai corporation established by Decree No.2 of 1985 (as amended) of the Government of Dubai, primarily focused on airline operations; it includes divisions and entities such as Emirates Skycargo, Skywards, and Business Rewards.dnata, whose principal office is at Emirates Group Headquarters, PO Box 686, Dubai, United Arab Emirates. dnata is a Dubai corporation established by Decree No.1 of 1987 (as amended) of the Government of Dubai, primarily focused on ground handling, cargo, catering, and travel agency services; it includes divisions and entities such as dnata Travel, Arabian Adventures, and marhaba.You can find out more about the Emirates Group here(Opens external link in a new tab).This Privacy Notice covers the Emirates Group and its websites, mobile applications, and mobile websites (collectively referred to as the “Platforms”), except where you are notified of another privacy notice by the specific Emirates Group entity that collects your personal information.The Emirates Group entity responsible for your personal information will be the entity that originally collects information from or about you. Where the collection and use of personal information is not addressed by this Privacy Notice, the privacy notice made available when your personal information is collected will apply.You do not have to provide your personal information to us, but if you do not provide certain information we will be able to provide only limited products and services to you. For example, if you refuse to provide mandatory travel information, we will not be able to transport you.This Privacy Notice applies even if you have purchased your travel or other products or services via a third party (such as a travel agent or holiday company). These third parties may also have their own privacy policies that apply when they collect information from or about you.We may amend this Privacy Notice from time to time to keep it in line with legal requirements and the way we operate our business.  If we decide to change our Privacy Notice, we will place updates on this web page and in the privacy sections of any relevant Platforms. Please regularly check this web page and the privacy sections of any relevant Platforms for the latest version of our Privacy Notice. If at any point we decide to make fundamental changes to our Privacy Notice, we will inform you by notice on our website or on the relevant section of any other affected Platform or by email.You might find links to third-party websites on our Platforms. Our Privacy Notice does not apply to your use of a third-party site. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of websites that are not operated by an entity in the Emirates Group, and we encourage you to read the privacy statements of any such third-party site.When you book a flight or vacation package or make other travel-related bookings with us, we will collect, process, and use personal information to manage all aspects of your booking.Types of personal information we collectThe types of personal information we collect when you make a booking or fly with us include your:NameTitleDate of birthAddressContact details (including email address and telephone/mobile number)Passenger Name Record (PNR) numberGenderPassport detailsEmergency contactContact details for next of kinBooking referencePayment card detailsLoyalty program numberNationality and other information for tax purposes (some countries only)Meal preferencesDestination address where required (i.e., the US)We use your personal information to:Fulfill our agreement with you and manage your booking or intended booking, including processing your booking, sending you your itinerary and other details relating to your booking, and contacting you if there is a problem with your booking (for example, by sending you a service message to inform you that your booking has not been completed).Update you on changes to your travel itinerary (for example, if a flight is delayed or canceled).Manage operations related to your journey, for example, ground handling (such as baggage and baggage claims), airport operations (such as check-in), fulfillment of special meal requests, and pickup and drop-off by chauffeur or transfer drivers (which may be handled by us or by third-party service providers).Manage your wider travel and products or services requirements (for example, liaising with and transferring your data to airlines, service providers (such as catering companies and ground and cargo handlers) and travel facilitators so they can facilitate your booking and your travel arrangements and minimize disruptions); this includes when you book a vacation package, hotel, car, or other ancillary service that may be provided by us or by third parties through our Platforms.Process payment for your booking, fulfill requests for refunds, and for accounting or audit purposes.Provide access to lounges and other airport products and services (such as welcoming services).Personalize the service and offers you receive (for example, by being aware of previous travel experiences, transactions, or preferences and tailoring the way we provide products or services to you based on your preferences and profile).Personalize the look and feel of our Platforms and our communications with you to align with preferences you may have told us about or that we have inferred from your use of our Platforms, your interactions with us on social media, market research, and previous transactions (see How we use your personal information for marketing purposes, profiling, and analytics, below).Provide the most helpful format and content for you by using location data received from our mobile Platforms (for example, prepopulating departure airport, airport code, and payment country) provided that you have enabled location services on your mobile device.Communicate and interact with you at different touch points throughout your journey (for example, we may use your contact information to inform you that your departure gate has changed or that you have not yet cleared through immigration).Communicate with check-in agents, flight crew, ground staff, airlines, accommodation providers, and other parties that are part of your journey regarding your experience, preferences, compliments, or complaints.Improve the products and services we offer or help us create new ones.conduct customer satisfaction surveys so that we can obtain a better understanding of how we can continue to improve the products and services we offer or help us to create new ones. During these surveys, we may collect personal information from you relating to your thoughts/comments about your experience with us.Market our products and services to you (details about How we use your personal information for marketing purposes, profiling and analytics are below).work with social media providers to provide you with advertisements within those platforms (details on How we use your personal information for marketing purposes, profiling and analytics are below)Manage our business such as for systems testing, IT maintenance or development training, benchmarking, and performance measurement.Use in connection with your online account or loyalty program membership such as Emirates Skywards and Emirates Business Rewards (details about Personal information we collect and use if you register an online account with us or register for one of our loyalty schemes are below).We may also use personal information for additional purposes as you authorize and consent to from time to time.Special categories of personal information we collect and useWe also collect special categories of personal information. The special categories of personal information we collect when you make a booking or fly with us include:Details about your health or medical conditionYour religion (for special religious flight bookings, such as Hajj travel)Your biometric dataWe use special categories of personal information to:Determine your fitness to travel (for example, if you have a pre-existing medical condition that may make it unsafe to fly)Provide you special assistance on our flights, at destinations or activities, or at airports (for example, when you tell us you need an oxygen tank or a wheelchair)Fulfill special dietary requirements you tell us aboutDetermine your eligibility for special religious flight bookingsIdentify you using facial recognition and other biometric technologies, which may be used by ourselves, our travel providers, or immigration authorities at the airports we fly to, including on behalf of governments, and to comply with local regulatory requirementsAddress a security or medical incidentComply with legal or regulatory requirementsWe may also use personal information for additional purposes as you authorize and consent to from time to time.Where your religion or health status could be inferred from meal preferences, we will not link this information or use it in any way other than to fulfill your meal request.We do not generally collect special categories of personal information from you (or those you are booking for), but where we do, we seek to minimize the collection and use of this information and handle it with extra care. We also share this information with third parties that help manage our business and deliver services, such as providing wheelchairs at airports, and other companies within the Emirates Group that help manage your booking or journey, and we transfer it globally. Click on the relevant sections below for further details about Sharing your personal information with others and Transferring personal information globally.When you (or any passenger traveling with you) provides us with special categories of personal information, you agree that you have voluntarily provided such information, and you consent (and the passenger consents) for us to use that information for the purposes for which it was collected.Advance Passenger Information (API)For passengers traveling to or through certain countries, we are required to provide details of the itinerary and booking details in our Passenger Name Record (PNR) system to border control, customs, and law enforcement officers at ports of entry and exit on your itinerary. This information is referred to as Advance Passenger Information (API). We will share API with relevant authorities as required and permitted by local applicable laws. If you do not provide this information, we may not be able to provide travel and may not be able to provide a refund or rebooking.Making a booking on behalf of another personIf you are making a booking on behalf of another person, it is your responsibility to obtain that person's consent to make the booking and share personal information with us (as anticipated by this Privacy Notice). We will assume that you have gained consent prior to making the booking. It is also your responsibility to represent that person during the booking process, which means that you will need to provide us with the information required to make the booking, such as the passenger's full name and passport details, and explain to that person how we will use personal information as set out in this Privacy Notice.  Where required by local laws, we would advise you to keep a record of the person's consent and provide them with a copy of, or link to, this Privacy Notice. Each person in a booking will be able to view the phone number and/or email address of the other persons in the booking and update such information. Any operational messages sent to one member of a booking will also be sent to the person who made the booking.When you register to use one of our Platforms or enroll in one of our loyalty programs, such as Emirates Skywards or Business Rewards, we collect, process, and use personal information to manage your registration. Once you register, you can manage your account and preferences.Types of personal information we collectThe types of personal information we collect from you when you create an online account or enroll in one of our loyalty programs include your:NameTitleDate of birthAddressContact details (including email address and telephone/mobile number)Country of residenceNationalityPreferred languageOrganization/company name, address, and telephone number and travel coordinator name and contact details (for Business Rewards)Once you create an online account or become a loyalty program member, the types of personal information we collect from you include:Rewards transaction details (such as points or Miles accrual, redemption, purchase, transfer, and gifts)Your travel preferences (such as your favorite seat, drink, or meal on flights, aircraft)Your personal lifestyle interests (such as in sports, theater, or hobbies)Marketing preferencesMedical needs in connection with your travelInformation about your travel coordinatorInformation about your family members (including when you enroll your child in Emirates Skysurfers or link your accounts with family members' accounts in a My Family Group)Death certificate and beneficiary information in the event of a request for the transfer of points or Miles from a deceased member’s loyalty program accountMembership number for a partner airline’s loyalty programWhen you create an online account or enroll in one of our loyalty programs, you will be asked to confirm that you agree to the online account and loyalty program terms and conditions. Your information will be shared between loyalty programs if you are also a member of a loyalty program with whom we have a partnership arrangement and with third parties who help us administer our online accounts and loyalty programs (further details on Sharing your personal information with others is below).How we use this personal informationWe use the personal information we collect if you register an online account or become a loyalty program member, together with the Personal information we collect and use if you make a booking or fly with us, to:Manage the online account or loyalty program in accordance with their terms and conditionsManage accrual, redemption, transfer and purchase of rewards (such as points or miles) and share personal information with any of our rewards partners (such as our airline, hotel, transportation and retail partners where points or miles can be accrued or redeemed) to manage such rewardsPersonalize the service and offers you receive (for example, by being aware of previous travel experiences, transactions, or preferences and tailoring the way we provide products or services to you based on your preferences and profile).Determine tier loyalty status and make offers and provide personalized service based on tier loyalty statusCommunicate and interact with you at different touch points throughout your journey (for example, in the event of service failures, compliments or complaints)Provide insights about travel behaviors (such as the industries and companies using our services for business travel) in order to provide industry or company specific offersExtend invitations to our eventsAuthenticate log-ins to your online account or loyalty program and detect and prevent fraud in connection with your online account or loyalty programWe may use personal information for additional purposes as you may authorize or consent to from time to time.Any information we collect will also be used in accordance with the terms and conditions of the online account or loyalty program.If you have any questions, compliments, complaints, or requests regarding any of our products or services, we will need to collect information from you, including your contact details, to enable us to respond to your query or provide the requested assistance. We will collect this information when you submit a form on our Platforms, send us an email, call our customer service center, visit a local office or retail center, or contact us via another form of communication, such as through social media or an online chat tool, onboard our flights, or in our lounges.Types of personal information we collectThe types of personal information we collect include your:NameTitleDate of birthAddressContact details (including email address and telephone/mobile number)Passenger Name Record (PNR) numberBooking referenceLoyalty program numberPassport copyDeath, marriage, or other legal certificate or power of attorneyDepending on the nature of your query, we may need to collect special categories of personal information from you so that we can properly understand the nature of your query or request. More details on Special categories of personal information we collect and useWe also keep a record of our communications with you, including call recordings, so we can monitor and improve the quality of our customer support services, comply with relevant legal obligations, and make and defend claims. If you visit one of our local offices or retail centers, you will be monitored by closed circuit television for security purposes. In each case, we do so in compliance with applicable laws.How we use this personal informationWe use your personal information to:Address your inquiry or other interaction with us as efficiently as possible.analyze the types of inquiries received to improve our products and services and interactions with our customersto authenticate your identity such as when you call our customer service centerManage any claims you make for compensation or otherwise.We may also use personal information for additional purposes as you authorize or consent to from time to time. We may from time to time hold contests, competitions, or prize drawings or make available promotional offers. If you want to take part in these events, we ask you to provide us with certain personal information; we also use this information to keep in touch with you about our products, services, and any special offers which we think may interest you.Types of personal information we collectThe types of personal information we collect include your:NameTitleDate of birthAddressContact details (including email address and telephone/mobile number)Loyalty program numberHow we use this personal informationWe use your personal information to:administer the contest, competition, prize draw or promotional offers and improve themTo invite you to join our loyalty programs.We may also use the information for other purposes you may authorize or consent to from time to time.Any information we collect will be used in accordance with the terms and conditions of the contest, competition, prize drawing, or promotional offer.Types of personal information we collectThe types of personal information we collect include your:NameTitleDate of birthAddressContact details (including email address and telephone/mobile number)Passenger Name Record (PNR) number Booking referencePayment card detailsLoyalty program numberMeal or drink preferences and other stated preferences (such as a preference for a particular seat)Lifestyle interests (such as in sports, theater, or hobbies)In the event of a medical incident on board a flight or in a lounge, we will need to collect special categories of personal information from you, such as medical information. More details on Special categories of personal information we collect and use are above.How we use this personal informationWe use your personal information to:Determine your eligibility to enter our loungesPersonalize the service and offers your receive (for example, if we know you are traveling for a special event, have indicated that you are a nervous flier or you have drink or meal preferences) and communicate relevant and timely information at certain touchpoints during your journeyManage Your Booking such as by fulfilling your request to change seatCommunicate and interact with you regarding your journey (for example, in the event of flight delays, gate changes or if you are late for boarding your flight)Communicate with other crew or ground staff regarding your experience, preferences, compliments or complaints, or a security or medical incidentManage duty-free sales or other paid transactions on boardProvide on board Wi-Fi in accordance with the wi-fi terms and conditionsUpdate you on flight delays, gate arrivals, baggage carousel number or other relevant updatesAddress your compliments or complaintsImprove the products and services we offer or help us create new ones.Manage security or medical incidentsWe may also use personal information for additional purposes as you authorize or consent to from time to time. Types of personal information we collectThe types of personal information we collect include your:NameTitleDate of birthAddresscontact details (including email address and telephone/mobile number) for you or for any brokers (where applicable)Details of passport or other forms of identificationPayment card or bank detailsHow we use this personal informationWe use your personal information to:manage your shipment and create a shipment record (airway bill)comply with legal or regulatory requirements for collecting and reporting on senders and receivers of cargoWe may also use personal information for additional purposes as you authorize or consent to from time to time. Types of personal information we collectThe types of personal information we collect include your:NameTitleDate of birthAddressContact details (including email address and telephone/mobile number)Passenger Name Record (PNR) numberGenderNationalityPassport detailsEmergency contactContact details for next of kinBooking reference Loyalty program number In the event of an emergency affecting your medical condition during your flight or journey, we will need to collect special categories of personal information. We will also collect information about your religion in order to fulfill your request to accommodate your religious beliefs. More details on Special categories of personal information we collect and use are above.How we use this personal informationWe use your personal information to:Provide in-flight or ground-based medical supportProvide accurate and updated information to persons directly affected by an emergency such as your next of kin and other relativesProvide information to emergency services, hospitals and clinics if you are admitted to them for your medical conditionCommunicate to embassies and consulates regarding their citizensArrange a hotel booking in the event that re-accommodation is necessaryWe may also use personal information for additional purposes as you authorize or consent to from time to time. Our Platforms use cookies. A cookie is a small file that is downloaded to your device. It collects information about how you navigate our Platforms and the Internet, which helps our Platforms provide better services to you and to tailor certain content. Cookies may collect personal information about you. For more information on how we use personal information when you use our Platforms and how to manage cookie settings see When and how we undertake analytics and profiling and Cookies below. We also monitor your journey on our Platforms via tools on our Platforms in order to ensure your customer experience meets expectations and to identify errors or issues.We process your personal information so that we can meet legal, compliance, and regulatory obligations; for legal purposes, such as to respond to a valid subpoena, claim, summons, or regulatory order; and to protect our property, rights, and interests and the property, rights, and interests of other persons.We also process your personal information for crime prevention and detection purposes, including the prevention of fraud in online payments and loyalty programs, for identity verification, for credit checking and credit scoring, and for accounting or audit purposes. If you visit one of our local offices, retail centers, lounges, or other properties, you may be monitored by closed circuit television for security purposes. In each case, we execute such monitoring in compliance with applicable laws.We collect personal information from third parties that you have authorized to provide your personal information to us (for example, your travel agent or another person making a booking on your behalf, your travel companion, your travel coordinator, co-branded credit card partners, duty-free retail stores, and social media and other digital platforms). We combine this information with the information we collect directly from you or about you for the purposes set forth in this Privacy Notice. More details on Sharing your personal information with others is below.We also collect personal information from individuals who refer you to our loyalty programs or products or services. We ask these individuals to confirm that you are willing to hear from us.We collect different personal information depending on your payment method (such as credit card, bank transfer, or cash). For example, for credit card payments, we collect the credit cardholder's name and address, the card number, expiration date, and CVC code. You may also choose to store your credit card details with us for future use. We do not store your CVC/CVV code (the security code on the back of a credit card).We collect your name, contact information, and details on your business card or online professional profile during, or in connection with, corporate events and activities. We collect this information in order to communicate with you and present you with business opportunities regarding our company, products, and services.These sections explain the legal basis for collecting and using your personal information; how we use personal information for marketing, analytics, and profiling; how we protect your personal information; the legal rights that are available to you; and how to contact us regarding personal information and this Privacy Notice.We only collect, process, use, share, and store your personal information when we are satisfied that we have an appropriate legal basis to do so. This basis may be because:We need to use your personal information to perform a contract or take steps to enter into a contract with you. For example, to manage your booking with us, to take payment for your booking, or to complete your travel arrangements.We need to use your personal information for our legitimate interests as a commercial organization. For example, we may record calls to our customer service center so that we can review how we handle calls and make improvements, or we may share your personal information with other Emirates Group companies to improve our products and services. In all such cases, we will look after your information at all times in a way that is proportionate, that respects your privacy rights and is in accordance with our Privacy Notice, and you have a right to object to processing as explained in Legal rights available to help manage your privacyWe need to use your personal information to comply with a relevant legal or regulatory obligation. For example, in some countries, we are required to provide API to border control, customs, and law enforcement officers at ports of entry and exit on your itinerary.We have your consent to use your personal information for a particular activity. For example, you may consent to us sharing with you special offers from the Emirates Group that we think may
interest you.We need to use your personal information to protect your vital interests. For example, we may need to report your medical condition to a hospital or clinic in the event of an emergency on board a flight.We set out more information about the legal bases on which we collect and process personal information in the table below. There may be one or more legal bases relevant to a particular activity listed in this table. The table may be amended and updated from time to time.We share your personal information in the manner and for the purposes described below:With other entities within the Emirates Group where such disclosure is necessary to provide you with products and services or to manage our business, including loyalty programs. We may also share your personal information within the Emirates Group to personalize the service and offers you receive (for example, by being aware of previous travel experiences, transactions, or preferences and tailoring the way we provide our products or services to you based on your preferences and profile); to develop a single view of our customers’ transactions, interactions, preferences, and behaviors across the Emirates Group; to improve the products and services we offer or help us create new ones; for marketing, profiling, and analytics as detailed in Personal information we collect and use for marketing purposes, profiling and analytics, below; and for the purposes described in this Privacy Notice. Click here(Opens an external website in a new tab) for a list of the members of Emirates Group;With third parties who help us manage our business and deliver our products and services, including loyalty programs. These third parties have agreed to confidentiality obligations and use any personal information we share with them or that they collect on our behalf solely for the purposes of providing the contracted service to us. These third parties include service providers who help manage our IT and back office systems, detect fraudulent transactions and security incidents, provide customer service center support, manage airport operations, manage communications and tailor marketing and advertising, verify payments such as banks and payment card companies, manage our data warehouses, provide services to administer our Platforms, provide internet services, host our facilities, provide airport ground handling and assistance, provide car services, and conduct research that helps us gain understanding of consumer interests.With bank and payment providers to authorize and complete payments.With governments, government organizations and agencies, border control agencies, regulators, law enforcement agencies, and others as permitted or required by law, in relation to API or other legal requirements as apply from time to time when traveling to or from a particular country, and to comply with all applicable laws, regulations, rules, and requests of law enforcement, regulatory, and other governmental agencies.With third parties whose products or services you purchase through our Platforms or otherwise, such as airlines (including our codeshare and interline partner airlines), tourism agencies, hotels, transfer and car rental companies, and tour and excursion providers, or to travel agents, including when there is a problem with your booking so that your travel agent can resolve it with you.We may share in aggregate, statistical form nonpersonal information regarding visitors to our Platforms, traffic patterns, and Platform usage with other entities within the Emirates Group or with third-party advertisers and social media and digital platforms that provide advertising.We work with third-party advertising and social media platforms to provide personalized advertising promoting our products and services in accordance with your preferences as detailed in Personal information we collect and use for marketing purposes, profiling and analytics, below.If, in the future, we sell or transfer some or all of our business or assets to a third party, we may disclose information to a potential or actual third-party purchaser of our business or assets.We use personal information to let you know about Emirates Group products and services we think may be of interest to you. This may be based on your preferences, derived from cookies, inferred from your interactions with, us including on our social media accounts, or based on market research. We may also let you know about our corporate services that we believe may be relevant to you in a professional capacity.We work with social media and other digital platforms to provide you with advertisements within those platforms. We provide them with your name and contact details (such as your email address or phone numbers). If these social media and digital platforms match profile information provided by us with profile information held by them, they will serve you our advertisements. The social media platforms will not identify you or share other personal information in your social media account with us.We will only send you direct marketing, whether about products and services from Emirates Group or from carefully selected third parties or partners, in accordance with your marketing preferences. We may contact you by email, SMS/text, or social media, or through other communication channels that we think you may find helpful. If at any time you would like us to stop sending you marketing material, contact us or choose the appropriate "unsubscribe" option set out below.To protect your privacy and to ensure you have control over how we manage marketing with you (and provided that you have indicated that you would like to receive marketing messages):We will take steps to limit direct marketing to a reasonable and proportionate level.We will only send you communications that we believe may be of interest or relevance to you and that comply with your permissions. Those communications may include, as appropriate:
Information about developments in the products and services available through our Platforms and those of our carefully selected partners (provided that we communicate these to you in conjunction with our own marketing);Information from other companies within the Emirates Group about developments in their products and services; andInformation from third parties offering marketing messages or updates related to their products or services. You have the ability to change your cookie settings to block certain types of cookie - this is explained in more detail in our Cookie Policy;You can click the Unsubscribe link that you will find at the bottom of the emails you receive from us, or you can unsubscribe by contacting us or changing your account settings to remove yourself from Emirates' marketing lists.You can unsubscribe from Emirates Skywards marketing communications by going to www.emirates.com, logging in to Skywards, and selecting My Account and then Personal Preferences. Within Personal Preferences, scroll down to update your preferences.You can opt out of mobile device messages or notifications from Emirates applications by going into Settings on your device and turning off notifications for the relevant Emirates application.if you do not want to be served with our advertisements within social media or other digital platforms, you can manage your preferences within these platforms.Be aware that if you unsubscribe completely from our marketing communications, we may be unable to notify you of tailored offers to meet your needs. If you do unsubscribe from marketing communications, you will still receive operational and service messages from us regarding your bookings, including messages notifying you when you have not completed a booking (such as abandoned cart emails or pop-up notices), loyalty program messages, and responses to your inquiries to us.AnalyticsWe aggregate personal information and remove any identifying elements in order to analyze patterns and improve our marketing and promotional efforts, to analyze Platform use, to improve our content and products and services, to customize our Platforms' content, layout, products and services, and to support our business operations and we may appoint third parties to do this on our behalf, as set out above in Sharing personal information with others.We gather certain usage information, like the number and frequency of visitors to our platforms. This information includes which website you came to our site from, which website you go to next, what browser you are using, your device ID, and your IP address. This data helps us to determine how our customers use parts of our platforms and research our users’ demographics, interests, and behavior to better understand and serve you. One of the ways we do this is by installing and using cookies on your browser or device. You can find out more about cookies and our Cookie Policy in the section entitled Cookies below.If you use buttons on our Platforms linked to social media or similar sites (for example, Like or Share buttons), content from our Platforms may be sent back to those sites and, depending on your privacy settings, may be privately or publicly visible (for example, to friends, followers, or anyone who has access to your profile page).ProfilingWe use personal information such as your date of birth, gender, country of residence, transactions (for example, payments made to us, Miles earned, and flights taken) and information derived from Cookies and your preferences for profiling. Some of the purposes for which we profile personal information include:To gain a better understanding of what you would like to see from us and how we can continue to improve our services for you;To personalize the service and offers you receive from us and recognize your loyalty so that we can reward you as part of our loyalty programs, including with invitations to special events;To provide you with tailored content online and optimize your experience on our Platforms;To provide you with tailored advertisements on other websites and social media and digital platforms;To share marketing material we believe may be of interest to you, including from other companies within the Emirates Group and from third-party partners;To help us operate our services more efficiently;To authenticate logins on our Platforms and detect and prevent fraud.Where required under applicable privacy laws,we will take steps prior to profiling your personal information in pursuit of a legitimate interest to ensure that our legitimate interest is not overridden by your own interests or fundamental rights and freedoms.You may have a right to object to us profiling your personal information. You can learn more about such rights in Legal rights available to help manage your privacy.The Emirates Group is a global business, which means your personal information may be transferred and stored in the United Arab Emirates and in other countries that may be outside your country of residence. Some of these countries have different standards of data protection than your country of residence.We will take appropriate steps to ensure that transfers of personal information are made in accordance with applicable law, and that we only transfer personal information to another country when:We are satisfied that adequate levels of protection are in place to protect the information; andThe transfers are fully managed to protect your privacy rights and interests and are limited to countries that are recognized as providing adequate legal protection or where we can be satisfied that alternative arrangements are in place to protect your privacy rights.To this end:We ensure that transfers within the Emirates Group are covered by an agreement between the relevant entities of the Group (an intragroup agreement) that contractually obligates each member to ensure that personal information receives an adequate and consistent level of protection wherever it is transferred within the Emirates Group.When we transfer your personal information outside the Emirates Group or to third parties that help us provide our products and services, we obtain contractual commitments from them to protect your personal information.When we receive requests for information from law enforcement agencies or regulators, we carefully review and validate these requests before disclosing any personal information.In the event your personal information is transferred to a foreign jurisdiction, it may be subject to the laws of that jurisdiction and we may be required to disclose it to the courts, law enforcement agencies, or governmental authorities in those jurisdictions.You have a right to contact us for more information about the safeguards we have put in place (including a copy of relevant contractual commitments) to ensure the adequate protection of your personal information when it is transferred.For residents of Australia, your personal information may be transferred to the United Arab Emirates, the United Kingdom, and where our servers are located from time to time, as well as other locations you are traveling to or from or as required by law.Protection of personal informationWe have implemented and maintain appropriate technical and organizational security measures, policies, and procedures to protect the personal information you share with us and to safeguard the privacy of such information. The measures we take include:Placing confidentiality requirements on our staff members and service providers;Destroying or permanently anonymizing personal information once it is no longer needed for the purposes for which it was collected;Following security procedures in the storage and disclosure of personal information to prevent unauthorized access to it; andUsing secure communication channels such as SSL (secure sockets layer) or TLS (transport layer security) for transmitting data that is sent to us. SSL and TLS are industry-standard encryption protocols used to protect online transaction channels.The security of information depends in part on the security of the computer you use to communicate with us and the security you use to protect user IDs and passwords; please take appropriate measures to protect this information.Here are some simple steps you can take to ensure your personal information is kept securely:Keep your booking reference confidential—When you make a booking, your journey will be assigned a unique booking reference (also known as a Passenger Name Record, or PNR), which will appear on the email confirmation or ticket of each person in your booking. It is important that you keep your booking reference confidential at all times. Other persons may be able to access your booking details through our system if you disclose your booking reference to them;if you are traveling in a group and would prefer that your individual booking details not be available to other passengers in the group, you may choose to have each person make a separate booking (to be paid for individually).Keep your Skywards number/Business Rewards number/customer log-in details confidential— You should not share your login details with anyone else. You should also make sure to log out when you finish using our platforms. This is especially important if you are using a publicly accessible computer.Beware of phishing—Phishing is when a malicious party represents themselves as someone else to gain information from you. Always check whether emails are actually from the sender they appear to be from. If in doubt, go directly to the sender's website; never click on links in emails, which may take you to clone websites that may collect and use your information illegally.Storage of personal informationWe keep your personal information for as long as is reasonably necessary for the purposes for which it was collected, for example, to manage bookings and provide you with information about relevant Emirates products or services, as explained in this Privacy Notice. When that purpose is fulfilled, we will ensure that your information is disposed of in a secure manner.In some circumstances, we may store your personal information for longer periods of time, for example, where we are required to do so to comply with legal, regulatory, tax, or accounting requirements; to maintain an accurate record of your dealings with us in the event of any complaints or challenges; or if we reasonably believe there is a prospect of litigation related to your personal information or your dealings with us.If you require further information about how we retain particular information please contact us.A cookie is a small file that is downloaded to your device. It collects information about how you navigate our Platforms and the Internet, which helps our Platforms provide better services to you and to tailor certain content.Cookies may collect personal information about you. Cookies help us remember information about your visit to our Platforms, like your country, language, and other settings and searches. Cookies enable us to understand who has seen which web pages and how frequently and to determine which are the most popular areas of our Platforms. They can also help us to operate our website more efficiently, make your next visit easier, and customize your view of the Platforms to reflect your preferences and activities. They also help us tailor our marketing and advertisements to you on our Platforms, other websites you visit, social media platforms, and your other devices.For more information on how we use cookies, please read our Cookie Policy, where you can also find information about how to delete cookies or block certain types of cookies. You should note that deleting or blocking cookies may affect our ability to provide platform services to you.See also our section on When and how we undertake profiling and analytics.If you are subject to laws that provide you with privacy rights, depending on certain exceptions and in some cases depending on the processing activity we are undertaking, you may have certain rights in relation to your personal information. Click on the links below to learn more about each right you may have:To access personal informationTo correct/erase personal information ("right to be forgotten") To restrict the processing of personal informationTo object to the processing of personal information (including direct marketing)To transfer personal informationTo obtain a copy of safeguards used when transferring personal information outside your jurisdictionTo lodge a complaint with your local supervisory authorityIf you wish to access any of these rights, we may ask you for additional information to confirm your identity and for security purposes, in particular before disclosing personal information to you. We reserve the right to charge a fee where permitted by law, for example, if your request is manifestly unfounded or excessive.You can exercise your rights by completing a form on our website which you can find here, by emailing us at privacy@emirates.com(Opens your email client) or by sending us a communication at Data Privacy Office, Emirates, P.O. Box 686, Dubai, United Arab Emirates. Subject to legal and other permissible considerations, we will make every reasonable effort to honor your request promptly or inform you if we require further information to fulfill your request.We may not always be able to fully address your request, for example, if doing so would infringe on the duty of confidentiality we owe to others or if we are legally entitled to deal with the request in a different way.Right to access personal informationYou have the right to request that we provide you a copy of your personal information that we hold, and you have the right to be informed of the source of your personal information; the purposes, legal basis, and methods for processing that information; the data controller’s identity; and the entities or categories of entities to whom your personal information may be transferred.Right to correct or erase personal informationYou have a right to request that we correct inaccurate personal information. We may seek to verify the accuracy of the personal information before correcting it.You can also request that we erase your personal information in limited circumstances where:It is no longer needed for the purposes for which it was collected; orYou have withdrawn your consent (where the data processing was based on consent); orYou have successfully asserted a right to object (see right to object); orThe information has been processed unlawfully; orThe information must be erased to comply with a legal obligation under European Union or Member State law to which the relevant Emirates Group entity is subject.We are not required to comply with your request to erase personal information if the processing of your personal information is necessary:For compliance with a legal obligation; orFor the establishment, exercise, or defense of legal claims.Right to object to the processing (including direct marketing) of personal informationYou can object to any processing of your personal information that has our legitimate interests as its legal basis if you believe your fundamental rights and freedoms outweigh our legitimate interests.If you raise an objection, we have an opportunity to demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate interests that override your rights and freedoms.You can request that we stop contacting you for marketing purposes.You can request that we not transfer your personal information to unaffiliated third parties for the purposes of direct marketing or for any other purposes.If you are a Skywards member or have joined our mailing list, you can manage your marketing preferences in two ways.You can click the Unsubscribe link that you will find at the bottom of the emails you receive from us, or you can unsubscribe by contacting us or changing your account settings to remove yourself from Emirates' marketing lists.To unsubscribe from Emirates Skywards marketing communication, go to www.emirates.com and log in to Skywards; then, select My Account and Personal Preferences. In the Personal Preferences section, scroll down to update your preferences for communications.Right to transfer personal informationYou can ask us to provide your personal information to you in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format, or you can ask to have it transferred directly to another data controller, but you may request such a transfer only where:The processing is based on your consent or on the performance of a contract with you; andThe processing is carried out by automated means.To obtain a copy of safeguards used when transferring personal information outside your jurisdictionYou can ask to obtain a copy of, or reference to, the safeguards under which your personal information is transferred outside of the European Union.We may redact data transfer agreements to protect commercial terms.Right to restrict the processing of personal informationYou can ask us to restrict your personal information, but only where:The accuracy of the information is contested, to allow us to verify its accuracy; orThe processing is unlawful, but you do not want the information erased; orThe information is no longer needed for the purposes for which it was collected, but we still need it to establish, exercise, or defend legal claims; orYou have exercised your right to object and verification of overriding grounds is pending.We can continue to use your personal information following a request for restriction where:We have your consent; orWe need it to establish, exercise, or defend legal claims; orWe need it to protect the rights of another natural or legal person.Right to lodge a complaint with your local supervisory authorityYou have a right to lodge a complaint with your local supervisory authority (That is, the authority with jurisdiction over your place of habitual residence or place of work or the place of alleged infringement) if you have concerns about how we are processing your personal information.Although you have a right to contact your supervisory authority at any time, we ask that you please attempt to resolve any issues with us before lodging a complaint.If we share your personal information with carefully selected third parties for the third party’s marketing purposes and you are a California resident, you may contact us once per year to request the name of those third parties and the categories of information shared. To do so, please send a request to us as set out below with valid proof of California residency. Please note that it may take up to 30 days to process your request.The primary point of contact for all issues arising from this Privacy Notice is our Data Privacy Officer, who can be contacted at privacy@emirates.com(Opens your email client) or by sending us a communication to the Data Privacy Office, Emirates Group, P.O. Box 686, Dubai, United Arab Emirates.If you have any questions, concerns, or complaints regarding our compliance with this Privacy Notice, we encourage you to first contact our Data Privacy Officer. We will investigate and attempt to resolve complaints and disputes as quickly as possible and in any event within the timeframes provided by applicable data protection laws.We use your personal information to:Legal basis for using personal information:Rationale for legal basis of legitimate interests:Manage your booking with us and your travel (and other products and services you purchase from us or access, such as our lounges), including processing your payment, contacting you with service messages, and coordinating with other service providers such as partner airlines, hotels, and car servicesFor the performance of a contract with you Personalize the service and offers you receive and personalize our Platforms and communicationsFor our legitimate interestIt is in our legitimate interest to promote our business, develop our relationship with you, provide you with the most relevant content on our Platforms (including through the use of cookies and location data where you have enabled location services on your mobile device) and in our communications, and interact with you in the most helpful and relevant way. To do this, we personalize our service to you and bring your attention to offers that may be of interest to you. It is unlikely that this type of activity will override your interests or fundamental rights and freedoms, which require protection of your personal data. If our activities take the form of marketing, we will seek your consent where we are legally required to do so. If you are a data subject protected by the GDPR, you may have rights to restrict or object to this processing; however, please note that doing so may adversely affect our ability to personalize the service, offers, and communications you receive from us.Improve our products and services and create new ones, including through surveys and by analyzing inquiries and interactions with us.For our legitimate interestIt is in our legitimate interests to improve our products and service based on our customers’ information, such as their transactions and interactions with us. It is unlikely that this type of activity will override your interests or fundamental rights and freedoms, which require protection of your personal data. If you are a data subject protected by the GDPR, you may have rights to restrict or object to this processing; however, please note that doing so may adversely affect our ability to personalize the service, offers, and communications you receive from us.Market our products and services to you, including through direct marketing, advertisements on social media and other digital platforms, and contests, competitions, prize drawings and promotional offersFor our legitimate interest; with your consentIt is in our legitimate interest to promote our products and services by providing you information about our offers and to seek to increase sales and customer engagement including by using third parties to support us in doing so. It is unlikely that this type of activity will override your interests or fundamental rights and freedoms, which require protection of your personal data. We will seek your consent where we are legally required to do so. If you are a data subject protected by the GDPR, you may have rights to restrict or object to this processing. If you do not want to receive such marketing from us, you can unsubscribe by choosing the relevant Unsubscribe option set out in our Privacy Notice.Manage your online account or loyalty program membershipFor the performance of a contract with you Provide you with special assistance, including determining your fitness to fly, providing you with needed medical equipment, and fulfilling special dietary requirementsFor the performance of a contract with you; to comply with legal or regulatory obligations; with your consent Provide you with customer support, including answering your questions about our products and services, handling your complaints and compliments, and fulfilling your requestsFor the performance of a contract with you; for our legitimate interestIt is in our legitimate interest to make sure that our business runs smoothly and that we provide customers with effective and timely support. It is unlikely that providing customer support will override your interests or fundamental rights and freedoms, which require protection of your personal data. If you are a data subject protected by the GDPR, you may have rights to restrict or object to this processing; however, please note that doing so may adversely affect our ability to provide you with effective customer service.Manage an emergency situation, including coordinating medical care; notifying your next of kin, governments, hospitals, and clinics; re-accommodating you on your travel journey; and handling a security incidentTo comply with legal or regulatory obligations; with your consent Identify you using facial recognition and other biometric technologies, including in connection with customs and immigrationTo comply with legal or regulatory obligations; with your consent Manage our business, including detecting and preventing fraud; analyzing our customers, products, and services; and using third parties to manage our products and servicesFor our legitimate interestIt is in our legitimate interest to support our business, including by preventing fraud and understanding our customers and how they use our products and services. It is unlikely that this type of activity will override your interests or fundamental rights and freedoms, which require protection of your personal data. If you are a data subject protected by the GDPR, you may have rights to restrict or object to this processing; however, please note that doing so may adversely affect your use of our products and services. Communicate with you regarding business opportunitiesFor our legitimate interestIt is in our legitimate interest to support our business by reaching out to individuals in their professional capacity to pursue commercial opportunities. It is unlikely that this type of activity will override your interests or fundamental rights and freedoms, which require protection of your personal data. If you are a data subject protected by the GDPR, you may have rights to restrict or object to this processing; however, please note that doing so may adversely affect our ability to present you with business opportunities. To comply with legal and regulatory obligations, including those related to crime prevention and security; immigration and customs; and subpoenas, claims, summons, and regulatory ordersTo comply with a legal obligation To manage legal claims, including to establish and defend a legal claimNecessary for the establishment or defense of a legal claimIf we need to commence or defend a legal claim, we may process special categories of data for the establishment, exercise or defense of such claim or when courts are acting in their judicial capacity
